Preliminary Inventory to the The Russian Review Records, 1941-1982.
Hoover Institution Archives
The Russian Review Records,
1941-1982.
73069
The Russian Review
11 manuscript boxes, 3 cubic foot boxes (7.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, subscription files, unpublished articles submitted for publication, clippings, and printed matter, relating to Russian and Soviet literature, politics and government, history, and political and social movements, before and after the Russian Revolution of 1917.
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is open for research however no more than 500 words may be quoted from unpublished manuscripts.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1973.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Russian literature.; Russia--Study and teaching.; Russia.; Soviet Union.; Soviet Union--Foreign relations.; Russia--History.; Soviet Union--Politics and government.; United States.
Container List
- Correspondence (Box 1.)
  - Incoming
    - 1941-1944
    - 1945-1953 (Box 2.)
    - 1954-1958 (Box 3.)
    - 1959-1967 (Box 4.)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 5.)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 6.)
    - 1970 (Box 7.)
  - Outgoing
    - 1942-1943, 1945-1949, 1952-1956, 1959, 1961-1962, 1965 (Box 8.)
    - 1966-1968 (Box 9.)
    - 1968-1970 (Box 10.)
- Increment, 1975 August (Box 11.)